three things I like about the Nordic
Track rw900 rower are the silent
magnetic resistance the auto adjust
technology and the endless amount of
trainer Le workouts through IIT on the
22-in touchscreen monitor this is a
solid high-tech rower for anybody
looking to spice up their cardio efforts
we got a whole lot to talk about today
so let's get right to
[Music]
it yo what's up everybody it's Jake back
in the Barb and garage gym and for
today's video I've got the Nordic Track
rw900 rower in for reviewed if you're
new to this whole process we got a lot
to talk about today but specifically
we're going to talk about some money
talk about some pros and cons some of
the features this rower offers and of
course who should or maybe should not
make this purchase now before I start
doing all that I got to let you know
that we've reviewed a ton of rowers on
baron.com and we did the hard part for
you and came up with our own best list
so if you want to check that out all you
got to do is search barbend best rowing
machines that article is going to pull
right up for you you can find out for
yourself which ones that we like the
[Music]
best okay so once again you know one of
my favorite things about this rower is
how quiet it is so Nordic Track has
implemented silent magnetic resistance
with this rower and so if you don't know
what magnetic resistance is basically
there's a flywheel that's you know
hidden back there it's you know it's
encased within and there's magnets that
are on either side of it right so when
you go up in resistance those magnets
you know are going to become closer to
one another and just basically increase
that resistance hopefully that makes
enough sense for you guys but the best
thing about it is really just how quiet
it is you know especially compared to a
water rower water rowers are really loud
and so that's something that you don't
have to deal with right here even the
seat gliding on this rail also you know
relatively quiet I love the 22in
touchscreen monitor you know it makes it
super easy to access all the trainer Le
workouts through iFit like I said
there's a ton of them but you know piggy
piggybacking off of that there's even
strength training yoga classes all of
that good stuff what you can do is
rotate that monitor right there you know
360° it tilts up and down and you can do
all those additional you know floor
workouts I guess we can call them while
streaming directly you know from your
rower still so you don't have to you
know stream from the companion app on
your phone or your tablet which the
companion app is really cool too all of
your stats are going to be you know
immediately transferred over it's one
profile so it all just kind of
intertwines I guess you could say and
that's you know sweet even when you do
you know those floor workouts it's going
to vice versa go onto your monitor right
here and that's a great way to you know
just keep you know tabs on your
overarching Fitness level which is
pretty sweet now as you're doing those
trainer Le workouts you're going to
experience auto adjust technology so you
know basically your trainer is going to
either increase or decrease the
difficulty of your workout for you which
is really cool but you can always you
know override that if you feel like you
need to now those things being said this
rower is not perfect there's still some
things you know that you're not going to
be too crazy about first of all it might
be the money it's going to cost you
around two grand that's kind of pricey
we're going to you know compare that in
a minute and kind of expand on the
pricing in general but you know if it's
out of your wheelhouse you can
definitely go find a cheaper one now
there's 26 levels of magnetic
resistance but in my personal opinion I
can't really tell that much of a
difference between level one and level
26 so while this will probably be fine
you know for a beginner maybe even an
intermediate rower if you're an
experienced rower you're I think you're
going to want to go and Target one that
does in fact offer you know a beefier
resistance another thing here is that to
really get the most out of this rower
you're going to have to pay for an IIT
subscription whether that be you know 40
bucks a month or you do one of the three
different yearly options which I'll talk
about in a second you're going to have
to do that and you know some people may
not want to do that if that's the case
definitely go find a more basic rower
now it doesn't fold this isn't always
the case with a lot of rowers but you
know it doesn't fold and you don't have
the option for vertical storage so if
you're tight on Space probably isn't the
best option for you and then lastly here
my personal opinion you know the handle
a little bit slick there's a tiny bit of
rubbery texture on it but overall I feel
like it's sometimes hard to you know
maintain a solid grip while I'm working
[Music]
out okay so once again the Nordic Track
rw900 it's going to run you right around
two grand well that's the base price at
least similar to the rest of the Nordic
Track gear that price is definitely
going to increase you know based off
some different variables the first one
being your choice of IIT subscription
all right so you can always pay 40 bucks
a month if that's the route you want to
go but if you want to save money in the
long run then it's definitely going to
be worth going after one of the three
different yearly options the one-year
plan is about 400 bucks two years is
about 700 and the three-year plan is
about 900 bucks now yes that threeyear
plan is you know extra $900 on top of a
$2,000 purchase but over that course of
3 years you're going to save about $500
so kind of just depends you know if
you're if you envision yourself I guess
you could say you know being locked in
you know for long run longevity of 3
years you know for IIT you can also
spend about 200 bucks for White Glove
assembly to have somebody assemble the
rower for you and put it in your room of
choice which is kind of nice so you know
the Allin potential total you could
spend on this rower it's about 3,200
bucks but the cool thing is that Nordic
Track does allow financing directly
through them over 39 month span and you
know as you're adding all these things
as you're checking out it'll
automatically adjust in real time for
you so you always you know get a good
idea of what you can expect to pay now
how does this price actually Stack Up
it's okay you know obviously it's it's
about double the price as you know the
concept 2 or really any other you know
straightforward No Frills rower you know
like that it's also about the same price
as you know similar products such as the
hydro wave which is also about 1,00
bucks now I will say with the hydro wave
I felt as if the resistance packed more
of a punch and that it also you know has
some features that I really wish the
rw900 had you know specifically the drag
effect so the more leg drive you create
and kind of you know the harder you're
pulling I guess that if that makes sense
the harder it is to row and that's not
the case with this one right here so if
you're kind of looking for that more
natural feel with an electromagnetic row
that Hydro wave is probably going to be
the way to go now whether or not you
know this row is worth it really just
boils down to your personal preference
we're all different we all want
different things in life and it's
definitely no different with a rower so
let's look at it this way if you're just
looking for a basic rower to hop on and
you know help you burn some additional
calories you know couple times a week
whatever it is then probably not you
know you're probably going to be better
off going after a more basic you know
cheaper rower however you know if you're
somebody who thrives off having you know
a teacher a coach trainer whatever you
want to call it and you want a high-tech
rower that offers an immersive
experience then yeah it probably is
going to be worth the money for you like
I said it really just boils down to your
personal
preference
so the rw900 does in fact have steel
framework including that steel rail
right here so it's nice and sturdy but
it's also going to lead to it weighing
about 160 lbs I know that sounds you
know pretty heavy but honestly whenever
you got to move it around with the
wheels it's really not that bad it does
have a 250lb weight capacity which it's
okay you know overall but there's plenty
of other rowers that have a higher
weight capacity if that's what you're
looking for now the handle it's all
right as I mentioned earlier it
technically you know has a thin layer of
rubber on it it's designed to help you
you know achieve a solid grip but a
little slippery overall and I feel like
there's a little bit you know left to be
desired I guess you could say with that
right there now I really do like the
foot pedals right here they're oversized
so you know pretty much every athlete
you know is going to be able to fit
their feet in there and then the nylon
straps really nice too it's just going
to make it really easy to lock your feet
into place now remember you do have
silent magnetic resistance there's 26
levels once again you know I couldn't
really tell a difference between 1 and
26 but you might so you know just keep
that in mind now you also have the auto
adjust technology it's really sweet it's
one of my favorite you know features
with this rower right here and that's
just you know it's going to prevent you
from you know becoming lazy complacent
you know fill in the blank with your
workouts that's nice how your trainer is
basically just going to be trying to
push you throughout the duration of each
individual workout now now 22in
touchscreen monitor already talked about
that a couple times now but remember it
does rotate 360° and it pivots tilts
whatever you want to call it up and down
so that when you're sitting you know
you're looking at it in a natural
position but then also like whenever
you're going to do your floor workouts
that'll be nice too whether you're
sitting or standing or laying on the
ground excuse me or standing and also
just the luxury of being able to turn it
and stream those you know additional
classes directly from the rower which is
pretty cool there's a lot of really cool
music options right there at your
fingertips and you know pair that with
the two 30 watt speakers you're going to
get you know some solid sound right
there however you do have bluetooth
capability so you can always you know
connect your earbuds and talk about
really being quiet especially if you
have you know roommates family members
whatever pretty much not going to be
making like any noise whatsoever with
this rower and then also you know if
you're somebody who really wants to you
know get an accurate reading of your
heart rate and you know your calories
that are being burned you can always
pair up your heart rate monitor and
that's going to be a really nice touch
for you as
well okay so remember you do in fact
have a steel framework right here and
that's including this rail so this rower
is pretty sturdy I don't ever feel as if
it's going to you know topple over on me
or anything like that now the seat right
here first of all it's pretty
comfortable as you can see you know
there is some give right there and
that's definitely a good thing you know
seats on rowers typically aren't very
comfortable this one is now as far as
actually you know gliding across this
rail it's pretty quiet and this is
pretty much the only noise that you're
going to be hearing as you're you doing
those rowing workouts and I'll show you
guys you know just in second exactly
what I'm talking about now as we move
further up I really do like these
oversized foot pedals and you know
especially paired with this nylon foot
strap because pretty much every single
athlete regardless of your foot size
your feet are going to be able to fit
right here and that's really nice and
then also you know just this nylon strap
in general just really allows you to get
a tight fit around your feet now this
handle it's really basic you know it's
just kind of straight across as you can
see and even though there is a little
bit of a you know rubber texture right
here it's pretty slick so if you have
sweaty hands definitely just be prepared
for that might want to keep a little
towel or something next to you now got
to talk about you know the star of the
show right now this 22-in touchscreen
monitor it tilts so you can kind of you
know position it the best for your neck
comfort and everything while you're
streaming your workouts but remember it
also rotates you know
360° so that way you can you know join
any of the other classes that are
available whether it be a strength
training yoga meditation all that good
stuff and perform it directly on the
floor and obviously stream everything
from here so you can avoid using your
phone tablet you know whatever now
there's so many classes to choose from
it gets kind of overwhelming and this is
the homepage so you're going to have
anything that's new goes straight up on
here right so the latest from IIT is
going to be right right here Harvest
hustle challenge up next for you
multiple challenges right here series
you can Browse by category right here
you can go to browse and this is going
to be even more this is basically the
full Library that's available and soakes
a second right here and there's filters
right here you can simply just filter by
anything workout series duration any
specific trainer that you like the
intensity all of that now you also have
a trophy case that way you know if you
do any of those challenges you're going
to get a trophy after you're done done
and that's just kind of nice you can
kind of keep up with your progress and
everything like that now there's also
this create option and typically with
Nordic Track stuff this is one of my
favorite things because Google Maps is
fully integrated it takes you somewhere
random so you just popped us into London
right here and you know with a rower or
a bike or anything like that you can map
out your own route and you're going to
have well especially with the treadmills
and bikes you're going to have automatic
adjustments to the incline and
everything like that but you know you're
just going to get like basically the lay
of the land kind of workout and it'd be
really really cool if you could do that
with the rivers that run through cities
and even ponds Lakes everything like
that but you just simply can't so
honestly this isn't very useful right
here um so hopefully you know that'd be
really cool if they can update that now
let's just go ahead I'm just going to
pop into a manual workout remember you
don't have any pre-programmed classes
you got to pay for IIT but you do have
this manual mode if you decide don't
want to maybe want take a break you know
whatever takes one second to pull
up there we go all right so you're going
to have a little warmup period it's
you're going to have all your metrics up
here at the top you know your 500 met
split estimated calories burn remember
if you connect your you know heart rate
monitor it's going to be an accurate
reading time elapse Strokes per minute
distance and there's some other metrics
that will pop up right there too now
let's go and end the warmup and I'm
going to get strapped in should have
already done that for you guys but you
know what it's all right we're still
here go ahead and get strapped in really
quick
and something I've noticed is that with
the 26 levels of resistance for me one
and 26 pretty much feel the exact same
so if you're you know an experienced
rower probably not going to be too crazy
about that but I also want yall to you
know hear the noise level really quick
so we're at level
one
it's pretty quiet right now let's go a
and go to
26 you can hear it kicking I don't know
if you can I can you can hear it kicking
in I mean if if I'm able to fill
anything it's you know a very small you
know jump up and resistance right there
so like I said you know if you're an
advanced Ro it's probably not going to
be the best option for you but you know
if you're a beginner or maybe even
intermediate level and you're just kind
of getting used to rowing in general
yeah this is a pretty good option so I
think this rower is great for anybody
who wants you know really techsavvy
equipment in their home gym and also for
anybody who just in general you wants a
trainer to lead them through their
classes on the other hand you know if
you're somebody who's working with a
tight budget or maybe you just want you
know a more basic rower in general you
can definitely find some cheaper options
that kind of you know fit that
description and then also you know if
you're an experienced rower and doing it
for a long time I don't necessarily
think this is the best rower for you CU
it might not be able to you know really
Pack-a-Punch the way you want it
[Music]
to all right well that's a wrap on
today's review over the Nordic Track
rw900 while it might not be what
everybody's looking for if you are in
fact looking for a modernized rower this
is a really solid option worth
considering thanks for watching y'all I
hope this video was really helpful I was
able to to break down everything there
is to know about this rower as always I
always say it and I'm doing it again
keep your eyes people for my next video
but for now head over to barb. comom
because we have a full written article
about this rower that I definitely think
you should check out all you got to do
is Google barbin Nordic Track rw900
rower review it's going to pull right up
for you you can go over everything we
talked about here today now I'm going to
go get a workout in I'll catch youall
next
[Music]
time